<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Asindu&#39;s journal</title>
    <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Asindu&#39;s journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://as1ndu.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of rationals</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/06/the-wisdom-of-rationals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/06/the-wisdom-of-rationals/</guid>
      <description>For years now I have been fascinated by prediction markets. The source of excitement is the idea is that you can use financial markets to do inference — just like machine learning.
A famous example of such prediction markets are the orange futures. The orange futures market is one that allows entities to buy oranges in advance. How it works, is that one can pay $1,000 to receive 1,000 oranges that will be delivered next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust minimization</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/04/quantifying-trust-minimization-with-hess-trust-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/04/quantifying-trust-minimization-with-hess-trust-theory/</guid>
      <description>Quantification of properties allows us to measure how well a system might perform. Quantification also allows us to effectively optimize systems, because if we can quantify something, we can know if things are getting better or worse. In 2017 Balaji S. Srinivasan, described how it’s possible to quantify decentralization of a project based on mining, client usage, dev commits, exchange volume, liveliness of nodes &amp;amp; ownership of capital by crypto address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic Bonds</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/02/fighting-of-disease-pandemics-with-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/02/fighting-of-disease-pandemics-with-defi/</guid>
      <description>When Bill Gates was asked in a Vox interview 1 on what he feared most, his reply was not climate change or nuclear war.
Mr. Gates was most worried about pandemics, deadly diseases that spread quickly over large regions, he goes ahead to cite some of the biggest &amp;ldquo;death charts&amp;rdquo; of history.
These &amp;ldquo;death charts&amp;rdquo;, where several spikes in which a large numbers of people died in a very short period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horus Theme</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/01/horus-theme-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2020/01/horus-theme-manual/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Try to refresh the site before it&amp;rsquo;s finished building.. I double dare you. Having nearly instant feedback enables you to have your creativity flow without waiting for long builds.&amp;rdquo; - Author of hugo
 I have used several static site generators, from Jekyll to Lektor and now Hugo. As for now, I really like Hugo but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a theme that matched my preferred aesthetics &amp;amp; functional tastes. That&amp;rsquo;s why I made Horus theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of work on layer 2</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2019/11/proof-of-work-on-layer-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2019/11/proof-of-work-on-layer-two/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Ethereum launched, they have had proof of stake on their road map. The main decision often cited from this transition is the claim that Bitcoin’s proof of work is a “waste of electricity”. Even the creator of C++ complained about it. But now I am talking about why we may need proof of work on layer 2 yet everyone is trying to get rid of it from layer 1 (the networking layer at which consensus is made).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Money As Tech</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2018/08/mobile-money-from-product-to-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2018/08/mobile-money-from-product-to-technology/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Money is probably the most common tech-narrative in the Ugandan the tech startup space. Unfortunately, the reluctancy of stake holders to upgrade it from a product to a technology will make it useless before we realise its ultimate potential.
The vision of mobile money that we dream of, is having people send &amp;amp; receive money amongst each other exclusively using 4 digit PINs and SIM Cards for authentication/identification of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain isn&#39;t working</title>
      <link>https://as1ndu.xyz/2018/05/why-blockchain-is-not-yet-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as1ndu.xyz/2018/05/why-blockchain-is-not-yet-working/</guid>
      <description>The current state There is a lot of hype about what the global distributed ledger aka &amp;ldquo;Blockchain&amp;rdquo; can do for society. A &amp;ldquo;trust machine&amp;rdquo; as some people call it, that will bring the power of finance, data sovereignty and inclusion to the people, hence rendering centralized intermediaries like Visa, Barclays &amp;amp; Facebook obsolete.
We shall achieve this by using a combination of robust, battle tested cryptography &amp;amp; game theory.
While this vision is plausible, realising it is not a easy as it may seem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
