<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Synchronising Life &amp; Dreams</title>
    <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Synchronising Life &amp; Dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://asindu.drileba.capital/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why blockchain is not yet working</title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/2018/05/why-blockchain-is-not-yet-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/2018/05/why-blockchain-is-not-yet-working/</guid>
      <description>The current state There is a lot of hype about what the global distributed ledger aka &amp;ldquo;Blockchain&amp;rdquo; can do for society. A &amp;ldquo;trust machine&amp;rdquo; as some people call it that will bring the power of finance, data sovereignty and inclusion to the people, hence rendering centralized intermediaries like Visa, Barclays &amp;amp; Facebook obsolete.
We shall achieve this by using a combination of robust, battle tested cryptography &amp;amp; game theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation of disease pandemics with DeFi</title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1995/08/mitigation-of-disease-pandemics-with-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1995/08/mitigation-of-disease-pandemics-with-defi/</guid>
      <description>When Bill Gates was asked in a Vox interview[^watch-the-video] on what he feared most, his reply was not climate change or nuclear war.
Mr. Gates was most worried about pandemics, deadly diseases that spread quickly over large regions, he goes ahead to cite some of the biggest &amp;ldquo;death charts&amp;rdquo; of history.
On talking more on these &amp;ldquo;death charts&amp;rdquo;, there where several spikes in which a large number of people died in a very short period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder for drafts posts in my blog</title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1995/08/draft-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1995/08/draft-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a draft post. Nor again is there anyone who loves or pursues or desires to obtain pain of itself, because it is pain, but because occasionally circumstances occur in which toil and pain can procure him some great pleasure. Nor again is there anyone who loves or pursues or desires to obtain pain of itself, because it is pain, but because occasionally circumstances occur in which toil and pain can procure him some great pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Atomic swaps &amp;amp; why they work.
An atomic swap is a trust-minimized mechanism that allows transactions to happen across several different chains.
For instance, one could seamlessly convert their BTC to LTC or Convert their Ether to Zcash. All without the need of a centralized exchange like binance.
No need for KYC, expensive fees, emails or Passwords all this occurs in your wallet.
This is the value prop of atomic swaps, and this article is an attempt clarify how they actually work under the hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Clarifying the blockchain proposition.
“If I knew what the killer app for blockchain is, I would be building it. Then we wouldn’t have time for this podcast” - Ian Grigg
Blockchain technology though trendy is elusive for some &amp;amp; most inforation out there seems to e repeating words like &amp;ldquo;decentralized&amp;rdquo; a coherent explanation. Even big brains like robin hanson seem to be consusef about what exactly the blockchain proposition is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Finally, the end of JavaScript?
Why JS is successful At about early 2010, a computer scientist forked Googles V8 js engine and made it run on the back-end/server-side and not the front end.
This could mean that, my barley accumulated skills of writing browser based programs could make me instantly capable of building applications that execute on the server. Hence I hopped the wagon.
JS became very complicated very quickly. It started with package manager Bower it was from fat &amp;amp; i liked work from his collaboration with mdo on Twitter Bootstrap &amp;amp; Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Mitigating BTC volatility with derivatives.
The biggest problem with Bitcoin is volatility. Bitcoins wild variation in price within short intervals. It is not even scalability like advertised.
it&amp;rsquo;s the price volatility that is keeping business from accepting Bitcoin. Any serious business (that isn&amp;rsquo;t trying to be anarchist or unkown/anonymous) will never accept bitcoin as a payment.
If I am a business &amp;amp; do $1,000,000 in revenues per year (while doing business &amp;amp; keeping the money in bitcoin).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Quantifying trust-minimization with Hess’s trust theory.
Quantification of properties allows us to measure how well a system might perform.
Quantification also allows us to effectively optimize systems, because if we can quantify something, we can know if things are getting better or worse.
In 2017 Balaji S. Srinivasan, described how it’s possible to quantify decentralization of a project based on mining, client usage, Dev commits, exchange volume, liveliness of nodes &amp;amp; ownership of capital by crypto address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Money, from product to technology.
Mobile Money is probably the most common tech-narrative in the Ugandan the tech startup space. Unfortunately, the reluctancy of stake holders to upgrade it from a product to a technology will make it useless before we realise its ultimate potential.
The vision of mobile money that we dream of, is having people send &amp;amp; receive money amongst each other exclusively using 4 digit PINs and SIM Cards for authentication/identification of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Proof of work on layer 2
Ever since Ethereum launched, they have had proof of stake on their road map.
The main decision often cited from this transition is the claim that Bitcoin’s proof of work is a “waste of electricity”. Even the creator of C++ complained about it.
But now I am talking about why we may need proof of work on layer 2 yet everyone is trying to get rid of it from layer 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Quantifying trust-minimization with Hess’s trust theory.
Quantification of properties allows us to measure how well a system might perform.
Quantification also allows us to effectively optimize systems, because if we can quantify something, we can know if things are getting better or worse.
In 2017 Balaji S. Srinivasan, described how it’s possible to quantify decentralization of a project based on mining, client usage, Dev commits, exchange volume, liveliness of nodes &amp;amp; ownership of capital by crypto address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>Regulation &amp;amp; The Digital Apartheid.
A few months back I got involved in a discussion on reddit that honestly pissed me off.
The context of the discussion was that;
Someone wrote a blogpost about how todo payment processing in with a payment processing company called Flutter Wave &amp;amp; submits it. A comment went like; I replied,
It’s really sad that society won’t accept certain efforts people are making because they are not knighted by a Scillicon Valley entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asindu.drileba.capital/1/01/</guid>
      <description>The Wisdom of rationals
Prediction markets like Augur are used to bet on events.
For instance you can bet on an event like “It will rain tomorrow”.
And if it does rain tomorrow, you get a pay off from people that bet “it will not rain tomorrow”.
There are three kinds of people who would bet in such a market. The pure gambler, this one doesn’t have the necessary meteorological information he is simply betting at random.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>